A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Public Relations, Series 27 FA369
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches, 1960-1964; 2
  - Local Government, September 22, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    Press Release re speech to Virginia Municipal League, Roanoke, Virginia; NAR handwritten notes of similar speech to League of California Cities (no date); NAR handwritten notes for "County Officers Ass(ociation)" Buffalo, New York 1/27/64.
  - "U.S. News & World Report", September 23, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    NAR interview.
  - "Modern Man's Dilemma in an Age of Tension", October 5, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    Speech (handwritten) to National Conference of Editorial Writers, Rochester, New York.
  - "Failure in Latin America - and How to Correct It", October 10, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    Speech, Western Hemisphere Day Dinner of the Avenue of Americas Association, New York City.
  - "On the Need to Restrain the Abuse of Federal Power", October 11, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    Speech, French Lick, Indiana, to Indiana Bar Association Convention.
  - "We're Living in a World Divided by Basic Conflict", October 12, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    Speech (handwritten) to Republican Western Conference, Eugene, Oregon.
  - Candidate for Republican Presidential Nomination, November 13, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    Speech (handwritten) to Associated Press Managing Editors Association, Miami, Florida.
  - Candidate for Republican Presidential Nomination, November 16, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    Speech (handwritten) to Metropolitan Press Club, St. Louis, Missouri.
  - The Rockefeller Republican Record, 1963, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    New York Republican State Committee publications.
  - Resumption of Candidacy Following John F. Kennedy's Assassination, January 3, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    Speech sponsored by Young Republicans, Portsmouth, New Hampshire.
  - Annual Message to the Legislature, January 8, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    Printed copy of message; mem 1/6/64 Hugh Morrow to NAR with "Inserts"; draft of Annual Message; printed excerpts "...to take the forward road..."
  - National Press Club, January 10, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    Memo 1/8/64 Hugh Morrow to NAR with suggestions about presentation of speech; NAR handwritten notes; draft of speech; copy "New York Times", President Johnson's 1/8/64 "State of the Union" message (marked).
  - "Freedom and Union", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    "Magazine of the Democratic World," 25th Anniversary Issue; NAR cover photo; formal address at anniversary meeting on North Atlantic Treaty Organization; receipt of award.
- Campaign Material, 1958-1972; 3
  Included in subseries 3 are memoranda to Rockefeller from Henry A. Kissinger, written for the 1964 campaign for the Republican presidential nomination, giving advice on Yemen, Cuba, Laos, Viet-Nam, NATO, and "California (primary) Strategy" (folders 108, 114, and 120). Also included is a letter to Rockefeller from Edward Teller suggesting the use of "small nuclear explosives" for defense (folder 120) and five other papers on foreign policy written by Teller and forwarded to Rockefeller by Henry Kissinger (folder 126). There are also several memos from Roswell "Rod" B. Perkins to Rockefeller regarding research and advice on various issues. Perkins was an attorney who served as Counsel to Governor Rockefeller for his first six months in office. He was actively involved in Rockefeller's early campaigns as a researcher and advisor.
  - California Campaign Trip, May, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    Itinerary; memos Henry A. Kissinger to NAR re "Phoenix Study," "Yemen Conflict"; memos Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR with "whistle-stop" material, civil rights, combating crime, ethics and conflicts of interest, Johnson's Eastern Europe speech; memo from Oren Root re campaign strategy; memo from Dr. William Ronan with draft of speech on Fiscal Integrity; intinerary for 5/22. Pamphlet; Economic Highlights of California, 1/17/64.
  - The Nelson Rockefeller Story, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    Campaign brochure, large magazine size (3 copies).
  - Rockefeller - He's done a lot, he'll do more, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    Campaign brochure.
  - Preserving a Free Press, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Commission on Critical Choices for Americans, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    Brochure announcing organization of Commission, and asking for "public participation, awareness and understanding."
  - Old Literature, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    -Campaign pamphlets, reprints and magazine articles -Pamphlet, 11/63; "Rockefeller and 'Right to Work'" -Pamphlet, 1/23/64; "Helping Small Business Grow" -Pamphlet, 1964; "Rockefeller Means Business!" -Pamphlet, 1964; "Women..." -Pamphlet, 5/11/64; "As a Republican, I Believe..." -Pamphlet, 1964; "Rockefeller and Labor" -Pamphlet, 1964; "Rockefeller and Our Colleges" -Pamphlet, 1964; "Rockefeller, Republican with Experience in Domestic Policy" -Pamphlet, 1964; Rockefeller, Republican with Experience in Foreign Policy" -Pamphlet, 1964; "A Comparison on Domestic Policies: Robert A. Taft, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Barry Goldwater." -Pamphlet, 1966; "The Massive Rockefeller Record." -Reprint, "Foreign Affairs," January, 1968, "Policy and the People." -Reprint, "Tax Policy," March-April, 1968, "Revitalizing the States." -Magazine, "Catalyst for Environmental Quality," Fall, 1970, "Environmental Crises Demand Worldwide Action" by NAR. -Magazine, "The Saturday Evening Post," Summer, 1971, "The Arts and Quality of Life" by NAR. -Magazine, "New York," (1971?), "The Aurelio Perplex..." Mention of NAR in article about Deputy Mayor Richard Aurelio and possibility of Mayor Lindsay running for President in 1972.
  - Platform Analysis Notebook, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    NAR handwritten notes; memo 5/14/64 Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR re meeting with Melvin Laird; analysis of 1960 Platform and 1962 "Statement of Principles and Objectives"; memos 5/13/64 Henry Kissinger to NAR re North Atlantic Treaty Organization and Yemen; 5/8/64 editorial "The Sacramento Bee": Rocky Obviously Is Best Choice for State GOP."
  - California Notebook, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    NAR copy.
  - Summary Positions Notebook, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    Position Papers of December, 1963 on Domestic Affairs: Agriculture, Balance of Payments, Civil Rights, the Economy, Health Insurance, Labor, School Prayer, Transportation, Foreign Affairs, Arms Control, Communist China, Cuba, Foreign Aid, Germany, Latin America, Middle East, North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Nuclear Testing, Soviet Union, United Nations, Vietnam, French recognition of Red China (with handwritten NAR notes). Section on pre-1964 positions.
  - Q & A Notebook, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    Governor's copy; 2 sections: Domestic and Foreign.
  - New Hampshire Notebook, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    Background for January 3, 1964 in Portsmouth concentrating on history and business at Portsmouth Navy Yard; sections on: Agriculture, Civil Rights, Economy-Labor, Area Redevelopment Act (ARA) Projects, Accelerated Public Works Program Projects, State Taxation Spending, Education, Natural Resources, Social Insurance and Welfare Services, and Foreign Trade.
  - Goldwater Positions Notebook, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    Sections on: Best Issues, Extreme Positions, Summary of Record, Domestic Issues, Foreign Issues, and Miscellaneous; some NAR notes on loose copies of material in back of book.
  - Memoranda re 1964 Campaign (Box 3, Folder 120)
    1/30/64 memo Henry Kissinger to NAR re Cuba 3/19/64 original letter from Edward Teller to NAR re California Campaign with emphasis on "deterioration of North Atlantic Treaty Organization" and need for a "joint North Atlantic Treaty Organization effort toward a defense against ballistic missiles," and the use of "small nuclear explosives which are required for defense." 3/23/64 Confidential letter, Charley Moore (Chair (?) of "Rockefeller for President") to NAR, re need for a "miracle" to win nomination; suggested changes in campaign which might provide "miracle," and allow NAR to survive loss. 4/24/64 memo from Wes Willoughby to NAR re "Goldwater, the Extreme Right wing and the California G.O.P."; list of "Extremists on Goldwater Delegation"; "Extremists" on Goldwater Kickoff Dinner Committee (including "Ronald Reagan, wants to repeal income tax"); John Birch Society information. 3/5/64 Henry Kissinger to NAR re "The Situation in Laos" (recent coup d'etat). 5/12/64 Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR re Senator Kuchel analysis of 25 Goldwater votes. 5/13/64 Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR re Henry Kissinger draft of statement on Malaysia. 5/13/64 Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR re Henry Kissinger statement on Cuba. 5/21/64 Henry Kissinger to NAR (original) memo re "Available Statements" on Cuba, Malaysia, Middle East, North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Defense, Zanzibar, Vietnam, Statement on Administration Philosophy, and Union of the Free. 5/21/64 Henry Kissinger to NAR (original) memo re "California Strategy." 1963 "Christmas Presents" list of names.
  - Civil Rights - Local, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    Press release 7/18/63 re enforcement of laws prohibiting discrimination; Conference Memo 1/6/84 Minister's Committee on Job Opportunities in Brooklyn; follow-up memo to NAR from Alexander Aldrich.
  - Civil Rights - National, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    9/6/63 Memo Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR re 6/17/60 Civil Rights speech annotated "to show which proposals have been picked up by John F. Kennedy." 9/30/63 Memo Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR: "Cut-Off of Federal Funds to States Practicing Discrimination." 10/21/63 Memo Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR: "Handling of Civil Rights Issues." Copies of Positions memos.
  - Economic Growth - New York State, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    Memo by Keith S. McHugh, Commissioner of Commerce re improvement of business climate in New York 1959-1969.
  - Economic Growth - National, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    Press release from American Bankers Association 2/25/63; memo T. N. Hurd to NAR re Gross National Product (GNP) and capital expenditures; memo John Deardourff to NAR re growth rate in United States and Europe; Chase Manhattan charts on business outlook and interest rates.
  - Federal-State Relations, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    Background memo from Division of Budget; NAR handwritten notes.
  - Foreign Policy, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    12/23/63 memo to Henry A. Kissinger to NAR with draft of speech; 12/27/63 memo from Henry A. Kissinger to NAR forwarding five papers by Edward Teller which Teller says grew out of conversations with NAR. Henry A. Kissinger says "I do not think we can use them in their present form. However, there are some ideas in them that we may be able to work into individual statements." The five papers are entitled: 1) The Need for Criticism; 2) On Defense; 3) The Union of the Free; 4) New Roots for Freedom; 5) On Russia.
  - Goldwater Positions (Quotes), 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    Goldwater quotes notebook (excerpts), some with NAR handwritten notes; Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins memos to NAR; Henry A. Kissinger memo re Tactical Nuclear Weapons in Europe (10/29/63); George Hinman re Goldwater statement "called...to our attention by Meade Alcorn"; news clippings re Goldwater.
  - Goldwater Candidacy Telegram, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 128)
    NAR telegram to Goldwater re: congratulations and invitation to debate.
  - Labor, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 129)
    Confidential memo to NAR from Victor Borella re amendment to the Davis-Bacon Act to include judicial review of wage determinations made by the Secretary of Labor.
  - Lubell, Sam, 1964 (?) (Box 4, Folder 130)
    Undated handwritten notes by NAR re "Transferability of Pensions."
  - Medicare, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    Confidential memo Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR, includes advice on rationalizing shift in position.
  - Miscellaneous Thoughts, circa 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    NAR handwritten notes on strategy, principles, philosophy, approach, etc. 1963 memo from Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins re July, 1963 meeting to discuss securing nomination for President in 1964; 13 handwritten pages by NAR about "Identification with Party." slogans, defense of freedom, prevention of monopoly of power, policies, etc., 12/13/63 "Important 'Image' Elements" memo for New Hampshire Primary.
  - National Defense Education Act, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 133)
    Memo from Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR re Act and summary of its first 5 years.
  - New Hampshire - Polls and General Issues, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    Memos from Lloyd Free with results of polls; memo from Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins: End each speech by asking for vote; NAR handwritten (and typed) notes 11/63 on issues; 12/13/63 memo on New Hampshire issues; memos from Lloyd Free profiling New Hampshire voters and latest (12/26/63) poll; undated NAR handwritten speech outline.
  - New Hampshire, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    Undated "Running-while-behind" notes (handwritten and typed ) for statement.
  - New York Record, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    Background materials.
  - Nuclear Test Ban Treaty, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    Copies of Treaty; 10/9/63 memo from Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins to NAR with recap.
  - "Opening to the Left", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    Memo 11/4/63 from Henry A. Kissinger to NAR re mentioning, in criticisms of Kennedy Administration, "Opening to the Left"; signifies Italian Government attempt "to wean the Left Wing Socialists away from a coalition with the Communists and make them a part of the Government."
  - Oregon, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    12/29/63 statement by William E. Walsh accepting State Chair of NAR campaign.
  - Per Capita Income, Taxes, Expenditures (by State), 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    Charts.
  - Republican Platform, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    NAR acceptance of Republican nomination for Governor, 8/25/58; Recommendation of the (New York) Republican Platform Advisory Committee, 8/25/58; NAR: "A Republican Approach to Great Issues" (7/11/60); Speech, 6/7/62, of Melvin R. Laird in House of Representatives: "A Declaration of Republican Principle and Policy"; Press release, 9/19/62, NAR acceptance speech accepting gubernatorial nomination.
  - Speech Digests, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    List of NAR major speeches 1959-1963, with copies of some speeches and digests; arranged in chronological order by year, but years are in reverse order as per memo dated 10/25/63 from John Deardourff to NAR.
  - Speech Memoranda, 1958, 1961, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    Digest of 1958 University of Minnesota study: "Do Republican Leaders Really represent Republicans?"; digest of NAR statement 11/14/61 re Nuclear Testing and Nuclear Test Ban; digest of NAR statement 4/29/63 re Kennedy Administration Failures; 7/7/63 "Minneapolis Tribune" story: "Young GOP Convention 'Mob Rule' Elects Goldwater People"; 9/7/63 memo from Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins' office re NAR positions on foreign aid and "list of our allies who have been confused by our foreign policy..."; 10/24/63 memo on Goldwater and the United Nations; digest of 10/12/63 Nixon "Saturday Evening Post" article "Khrushchev's Hidden Weakness"; Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins memo re 3 proposed amendments to United States Constitution: 1) Amendment Procedure, 2) State Legislature Apportionment (would overrule United States Supreme Court decision Baker v. Carr (one man-one vote)), 3) create "Court of the Union" to review Supreme Court decisions relating to rights reserved to the States; Roswell B. "Rod" Perkins memo (undated) to NAR re Notre Dame Speech Proposal on Compulsory Arbitration.
  - Speeches, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    Press release, 10/27/61, speech to National Convention of Sigma Delta Chi; Press release, 1/30/62, Special Message to Legislature on Mental Disability; Press release, 10/14/63, Buffalo speech to United Steelworkers Workmen's Compensation Committee; Press release, 10/23/63, San Francisco, speech to League of California Cities; May 16, 1964 news clippings re Oregon primary victory; draft of editorial for "Los Angeles (?) Times."
  - Draft Staff Papers, circa 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    Poverty; Civil Rights; Blighted Areas; Education; Job Opportunity; Housing; Law Enforcement; Health; Mental Health; Youth; The Aging; The Environment; Recreation; The Arts; Agriculture; Transportation; Consumer Protection; Government spending & Economic Resources; The Federal System; The American Indian.
  - Vietnam Background Book, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    History 1954-1963; United States Programs since 1964-Military; United States Programs since 1964-Pacification; United States Programs after 1964-Creation of a National Government.
  - Domestic Problems of United States, Statistical Workbook, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    Staff Report for Republican Governors' Association Policy Committee (Working Document); NAR Chair of Policy Committee; on copy of letter transmitting Workbook to Governor Love, NAR handwritten note: "Ann, I want to get copies of this book for my brothers, my children and all nieces and nephews."
  - Fact Sheets on Foreign Policy, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    Balance of Payments, Berlin, China, Defense, East-West Trade, Eastern Europe, European Economic Community, Middle East, North American Treaty Organization, Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.
  - Presidential Campaign, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    Memo to NAR from Dr. Hurd re Federal Aid Programs and Taxes; undated "Washington Post" editorial; Statement: "Let the People Speak"; NAR handwritten notes; Republican Governors' Association, Boston, 5/13/68, schedule of witnesses before Regional Platform Hearing; Memo to NAR from Henry A. Kissinger, 6/9/68, "Where Are We Now in the Campaign?"; 6/9/68 Minutes of Meeting on National Needs after the [Robert] Kennedy Assassination with John Gardner, Caryl Haskins and HK (Nancy Maginess took notes); Guest list, Rockefeller Dinner, 6/12/68 (California ?); NAR Schedule for June 17, 1968, New York, Pennsylvania & District of Columbia; NAR Schedule June 18-22, 1968, New York, Cleveland, District of Columbia, Virginia, Delaware; Memo from Keith S. McHugh, 6/13/68, to all members of Post Vietnam Planning Committee; memo to NAR from Hugh Morrow, 6/27/68, re proposed speech on Conventional Arms; "personal" letter, 6/27/68, to NAR from Samuel Lubell with advice on campaign issues; 7/2/68 press releases on foreign policy and gun control; copy of speech "Why I Seek the Presidency" with NAR handwritten edits; memo 7/3/68 to NAR from High Morrow re upcoming San Francisco speech on 7/8/68 and copy of speech; 7/3/68 memo to NAR from Joe Canzeri and Ken Hoeck with Hawaii trip information; 7/5/68 speech on opening of campaign headquarters in Hawaii; Hawaii information notebook (brown binder); news clippings.
  - Art, 1966, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    Correspondence, photos and catalogues of David Smith sculpture; recommendations by Dorothy Miller.
  - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    Dr. Franz Winkler notes of a meeting on 10/14/70; memos on issues; October 17-30, 1970 schedule; President Nixon letter dated 9/26/70 to NAR with copy of J. Edgar Hoover's "Open Letter to College Students" and copy of Harry Albright's summary of Hoover letter; Alton Marshall 10/70 memo to NAR re Kennedy Airport Expansion; Abe Lavine 10/70 memo to NAR re Correction Officers Demonstration in New York City on 10/13; memos re "Youth Environmental Service"; Jerry Danzig 10/17//70 memo re Puerto Rican floods of early October and appearance by NAR at telethon to benefit flood relief; speech 10/22/70 for Council on the Arts grant award, with information from the Council on the award; ron Maiorana 10/20/70 memos (2) to NAR for "New York Times" "debate-interview," first memo on "random thoughts," and second on the "ground rules"; press release (undated) from New York State Department of Labor re employment and unemployment in New York in August, 1970.
  - Correspondence with Living Rockefeller Family Members (CLOSED FOLDER), 1964. 1968 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted material